<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Events on Penn CS Theory Group</title><link>https://theory.cis.upenn.edu/post/</link><description>Recent content in Events on Penn CS Theory Group</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Thu, 02 Mar 2017 12:00:00 -0500</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://theory.cis.upenn.edu/post/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Theory Seminar: Kate Donahue</title><link>https://theory.cis.upenn.edu/post/kated/</link><pubDate>Fri, 08 Sep 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://theory.cis.upenn.edu/post/kated/</guid><description>This week&amp;rsquo;s theory seminar speaker is Kate Donahue of Cornell University. As usual, the talk will take place in Room 401B, 3401 Walnut Street on Friday 12-1 PM. Talk and speaker details are included below
Title: Stability, Optimality, and Fairness in Federated Learning
Abstract: Federated learning is a distributed learning paradigm where multiple agents, each only with access to local data, jointly learn a global model. There has recently been an explosion of research aiming not only to improve the accuracy rates of federated learning, but also provide certain guarantees around social good properties such as total error or fairness.</description></item><item><title>Theory Seminar: Jon Schneider</title><link>https://theory.cis.upenn.edu/post/jons/</link><pubDate>Fri, 01 Sep 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://theory.cis.upenn.edu/post/jons/</guid><description>The theory seminar will restart this week with a talk by Jon Schneider of Google Research. The talk will take place at Room 401B, 3401 Walnut Street from 12-1 PM on Friday.
Title: U-Calibration: Forecasting for an Unknown Agent
Abstract: We will discuss the problem of evaluating forecasts of binary events whose predictions are consumed by rational agents who take an action in response to a prediction, but whose utilities are unknown to the forecaster.</description></item><item><title>Theory Seminar: Mordecai Golin</title><link>https://theory.cis.upenn.edu/post/modecaigolin/</link><pubDate>Fri, 05 May 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://theory.cis.upenn.edu/post/modecaigolin/</guid><description>The speaker for this week&amp;rsquo;s theory seminar is Mordecai Golin from HKUST. As usual, the talk will take place on Friday 5/5 at 1PM in Levine 307.
Title: AIFV-m Coding and Finding the Cheapest Markov Chain Mordecai Golin. Hong Kong UST
Abstract: Binary AIFV-m codes are a relatively new method for lossless compression. They encode using an m-tuple of coding trees rather than the single tree used by Huffman coding. Their advantage is better proven redundancy than Huffman codes; their disadvantage is a slight decoding delay.</description></item><item><title>Theory Seminar: Sergei Vassilvitskii</title><link>https://theory.cis.upenn.edu/post/sergeivassilvitskii/</link><pubDate>Fri, 28 Apr 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://theory.cis.upenn.edu/post/sergeivassilvitskii/</guid><description>The speaker for the theory seminar on 4/28 is Sergei Vassilvitskii from Google. As usual, the talk will take place at 1pm in Levine 307.
Title: New advances in &amp;lsquo;Algorithms with Predictions&amp;rsquo;
Abstract: The theoretical study of algorithms and data structures has been bolstered by worst-case analysis, where we prove bounds on the running time, space, approximation ratio, competitive ratio, or other measure that holds even in the worst case. In practice, however, we often do not face worst-case scenarios, and the question arises of how we can tune our algorithms to work even better on the kinds of instances we are likely to see, while ideally keeping a rigorous formal framework similar to what we have developed through worst-case analysis.</description></item><item><title>Theory Seminar: Abhishek Shetty</title><link>https://theory.cis.upenn.edu/post/abhishekshetty/</link><pubDate>Fri, 21 Apr 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://theory.cis.upenn.edu/post/abhishekshetty/</guid><description>The speaker for this week&amp;rsquo;s theory seminar is Abhishek Shetty from UC Berkeley. The talk will take place on Friday 4/21 at 1PM in Levine 307.
Title: Optimal PAC Bounds without Uniform Convergence
Abstract: In statistical learning theory, determining the sample complexity of realizable binary classification for VC classes was a long-standing open problem. The results of Simon and Hanneke established sharp upper bounds in this setting. However, the reliance of their argument on the uniform convergence principle limits its applicability to more general learning settings such as multiclass classification.</description></item><item><title>Theory Seminar: Xi Chen</title><link>https://theory.cis.upenn.edu/post/xichen/</link><pubDate>Fri, 14 Apr 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://theory.cis.upenn.edu/post/xichen/</guid><description>The speaker for this week&amp;rsquo;s theory seminar is Xi Chen from Columbia University. As usual, the talk will take place on Friday 4/14 at Levine 307 from 1-2 PM.
Title: Smoothed Complexity of SWAP for Graph Partitioning
Abstract: Many algorithms and heuristics that work well in practice have poor performance under the worst-case analysis, due to delicate pathological instances that one may never encounter. To bridge this theory-practice gap, Spielman and Teng introduced the smoothed analysis framework which can be viewed as a hybrid of the classical worst-case and average-case analyses.</description></item><item><title>Theory Seminar: Rajesh Jayaram</title><link>https://theory.cis.upenn.edu/post/rajeshjayaram/</link><pubDate>Fri, 07 Apr 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://theory.cis.upenn.edu/post/rajeshjayaram/</guid><description>Our speaker for the Theory Seminar on 4/7 will be Rajesh Jayaram of Google Research. As usual, the talk will take place at 1pm in Levine 307.
Title: Streaming Euclidean MST to a Constant Factor
Abstract: We consider the problem of computing the cost of the Euclidean Minimum Spanning Tree (MST) of an n-point set X in R^d, where the points in X are presented in a stream. In low dimensions, (1+ε) approximations are possible in sublinear (in n) space [Frahling, Indyk, Sohler, SoCG &amp;lsquo;05].</description></item><item><title>Theory Seminar: Zihan Tan</title><link>https://theory.cis.upenn.edu/post/zihantan/</link><pubDate>Fri, 24 Mar 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://theory.cis.upenn.edu/post/zihantan/</guid><description>The theory seminar is back in Levine 307 this Friday 3/24 at 1PM, featuring Zihan Tan from Rutgers University.
Title: A Subpolynomial Approximation Algorithm for Graph Crossing Number in Low-Degree Graphs
Abstract: Graph Crossing Number is a fundamental and extensively studied problem with wide ranging applications. In this problem, the goal is to draw an input graph G in the plane so as to minimize the number of crossings between the images of its edges.</description></item><item><title>Theory Seminar: Kamesh Munagala</title><link>https://theory.cis.upenn.edu/post/kamesh/</link><pubDate>Thu, 16 Mar 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://theory.cis.upenn.edu/post/kamesh/</guid><description>This week, to account for visit day, theory seminar will be on Thursday March 16 at noon (instead of Friday at 1PM). It will be held in the PCPSE (Perelman Center for Political Science and Economics), in the Dean’s forum on the second floor.
We are excited to have Kamesh Munagala from Duke speaking. Please find the abstract and bio below.
Abstract: We study the classical Bayesian auction setting with a twist: Between the revenue maximizing seller and the buyers lies an intermediary that is better informed about the buyer values.</description></item><item><title>Theory Seminar: Huan Li</title><link>https://theory.cis.upenn.edu/post/huan/</link><pubDate>Fri, 10 Mar 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://theory.cis.upenn.edu/post/huan/</guid><description>Our speaker for this week&amp;rsquo;s theory seminar is Huan Li, a PhD student here at Penn. The talk will take place in Levine 307 on Friday 3/10 at 1pm.
Title: On Weighted Graph Sparsification by Linear Sketching
Abstract: A seminal work of [Ahn-Guha-McGregor, PODS'12] showed that one can compute a cut sparsifier of an unweighted undirected graph by taking a near-linear number of linear measurements on the graph. Subsequent works also studied computing other graph sparsifiers using linear sketching, and obtained near-linear upper bounds for spectral sparsifiers [Kapralov-Lee-Musco-Musco-Sidford, FOCS'14] and first non-trivial upper bounds for spanners [Filtser-Kapralov-Nouri, SODA'21].</description></item><item><title>Theory Seminar: Sepehr Assadi</title><link>https://theory.cis.upenn.edu/post/sepehr/</link><pubDate>Fri, 03 Mar 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://theory.cis.upenn.edu/post/sepehr/</guid><description>We are excited to announce that this week&amp;rsquo;s speaker is Sepehr Assadi. The talk will take place on Friday, 3/3 at 1pm in Levine 307.
Title: An Asymptotically Optimal Algorithm for Maximum Matching in Dynamic Streams
Abstract: We present an algorithm for the maximum matching problem in dynamic (insertion-deletions) streams with asymptotically optimal space complexity: for any n-vertex graph, our algorithm with high probability outputs an α-approximate matching in a single pass using O(n^2/α^3) bits of space.</description></item></channel></rss>